mayomedicallaboratories.com 2008-05-07

# Privacy Policy - Mayo Medical Laboratories

MayoMedicalLaboratories.com is committed to protecting your online privacy. We feel it is important for you to know how we handle the information we receive from you via the Internet. In general, you can visit www.MayoMedicalLaboratories.com without revealing any personal information. However, you may be required to provide information to gain access to some of our content and services, as explained below. 

MayoMedicalLaboratories.com may contain links to Web sites operated by third parties. MayoMedicalLaboratories.com has no control over the privacy policies and practices of such third-party sites, and if you have any concerns, you are urged to review the terms of those sites for more information about the policies applicable to those sites. 

##  IP addresses 

We collect and log the IP address of all visitors to MayoMedicalLaboratories.com. An IP address is a number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. IP addresses allow computers and servers to recognize and communicate with one another. We collect IP address information so we can properly administer our system and gather aggregate information about how our site is being used, including the pages visitors are viewing. To maintain your anonymity, we do not associate IP addresses with records containing personal information. We will use IP address information, however, to personally identify you in order to enforce our legal rights or when required to do so by law enforcement authorities.

##  How we use 'cookies' 

As you probably know, "cookies" are small pieces of information that some Web sites store on your computer's hard drive when you visit them. Like many other Web sites, MayoMedicalLaboratories.com uses cookies to provide us with information relating to the sources of our site traffic. Collecting this information, however, does not allow us to personally identify you. 

Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies but allow you to modify security settings so that you can approve or reject cookies on a case-by-case basis. 

##  Registration information

We collect personal information that you choose to share with us in the registration section of our site. This information includes your e-mail address and your answers to questions about your areas of interest. We use this information to tailor our site to the data you entered. Information from registration is saved to our database. This enables you to access resources only available to registered users and your status as a client of Mayo Medical Laboratories. This saved information is collected only with your permission and may be updated or deleted by you at any time. If you choose to not provide the information required for registration, you may not register with the site and you will not be able to access information reserved for registered users.

##  Surveys 

You may be asked to complete surveys when you visit MayoMedicalLaboratories.com. We use information from surveys to better understand the needs of our users. We may share information from surveys with third parties who perform data management services for our site. Also, we may share information from surveys in an aggregated, de-identified form with third parties with whom we have a business relationship. 

##  How to delete any information you have provided 

It's not technologically possible for us to remove from our servers every record of the information you've provided to MayoMedicalLaboratories.com. The need to back up our systems to protect information from inadvertent loss means that a copy of your personal information may exist in a non-erasable form that will be difficult or impossible for us to locate. Nevertheless, upon receiving your deletion request, all information you’ve provided that’s stored in the databases we actively use for research and daily business activities, and other readily searchable media, will be deleted.   
Remember: Unsubscribing from our e-mail newsletter will not delete any information you have entered into the site as outlined above. 

##  What we provide to third parties 

Except as noted above for surveys, MayoMedicalLaboratories.com does not provide any third-party access to your information unless the information has been aggregated and de-identified to make it anonymous. We may provide third parties with aggregate statistics about our visitors, traffic patterns and related site information. These data reflect site-usage patterns gathered during visits to our Web site each month, but they do not contain behavioral or identifying information about any individual. 

##  Aggregate information 

We may use general traffic, site usage and length-of-stay information in reports to firms with which we have a business relationship. This sort of information is shared only in aggregate and does not personally identify you. 

##  Children's privacy 

This site is intended for adults age 18 and older. It is not intended for or designed to attract persons under the age of 18. 

E-mail communications, newsletter, feedback forms and related services   
MayoMedicalLaboratories.com provides you with the opportunity to receive communications from us. You can sign up for a free e-mail communications. You can unsubscribe from these communications at any time. 

Communication that you send to us via the e-mail links or feedback forms on our site may be shared with a Customer Service representative, employee, medical expert or agent that is most able to address your inquiry. We make every effort to respond in a timely fashion once communications are received. Once we have responded to your communication, it is discarded or archived, depending on the nature of the inquiry. 

The functionality on our site does not provide a completely secure and confidential means of communication. It's possible that your communication may be accessed or viewed by another Internet user while in transit to us. If you wish to keep your communication private, do not use electronic communication means to contact us. 

##  Complaint process 

If you have a complaint or problem, or if you believe your privacy rights have been violated, you may e-mail us by clicking the "Contact us" link at the bottom of any page. If you don't receive adequate resolution of a privacy-related problem, you may write to MayoMedicalLaboratories.com's Security and Privacy Officer at: 

Security and Privacy Officer   
MayoMedicalLaboratories.com   
3050 Superior Drive NW   
Rochester, MN 55905 

If you've contacted MayoMedicalLaboratories.com about a privacy-related concern and you do not believe your problem has been addressed, you may file a complaint with the Mayo Clinic Chief Security Officer by dialing the Mayo Clinic general number at 507.284.2511 and asking for the Chief Security Officer. 

##  Changes to our Privacy policy 

We will occasionally update this Privacy policy. You're encouraged to review the policy to be informed of how this site is protecting your information.
